<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="ranger-beast-master.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/knightoffline/Aurora_flex/main/user-knightoffline/ranger-beast-master.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Beast Master" type="Archetype" source="Offline Knights" id="OK_ARCHETYPE_RANGER_BEAST_MASTER">
		<supports>Ranger Archetype</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The Beast Master archetype embodies a friendship between the civilized races and the beasts of the world. United in focus, beast and ranger work as one to fight the monstrous foes that threaten civilization and the wilderness alike. Emulating the Beast Master archetype means committing yourself to this ideal, working in partnership with an animal as its companion and friend.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_PRIMAL_COMPANION" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_EXCEPTIONAL_TRAINING" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_BESTIAL_FURY" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_SHARE_SPELLS" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>The Beast Master archetype embodies a friendship between the civilized races and the beasts of the world.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_PRIMAL_COMPANION" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_EXCEPTIONAL_TRAINING" level="7" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_BESTIAL_FURY" level="11" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_SHARE_SPELLS" level="15" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Primal Companion" type="Archetype Feature" source="Offline Knights" id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_PRIMAL_COMPANION">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_RANGER_BEAST_MASTER_PRIMAL_COMPANION</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>This 3rd-level feature replaces the Ranger's Companion feature.</p>
			<p class="indent">You magically summon a primal beast, which draws strength from your bond with nature. The beast is friendly to you and your companions and obeys your commands. Choose its stat block-Beast of the Land, Beast of the Sea, or Beast of the Sky-which uses your proficiency bonus (PB) in several places. You also determine the kind of animal the beast is, choosing a kind appropriate for the stat block. Whatever kind you choose, the beast bears primal markings, indicating its mystical origin.</p>
			<p class="indent">In combat, the beast acts during your turn. It can move and use its reaction on its own, but the only action it takes is the Dodge action, unless you take a bonus action on your turn to command it to take another action. That action can be one in its stat block or some other action. You can also sacrifice one of your attacks when you take the Attack action to command the beast to take the Attack action. If you are incapacitated, the beast can take any action of its choice, not just Dodge.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the beast has died within the last hour, you can use your action to touch it and expend a spell slot of 1st level or higher. The beast returns to life after 1 minute with all its hit points restored. When you finish a long rest, you can summon a different primal beast. The new beast appears in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of you, and you choose its stat block and appearance. If you already have a beast from this feature, it vanishes when the new beast appears. The beast also vanishes if you die.</p>
		</description>
		<rules>
			<select type="Companion" name="PRIMAL Companion" supports="Beast,(Tiny||Small||Medium),(1/4||1/8||0)" />
			<stat name="companion:ac" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="companion:attack" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="companion:damage" value="proficiency" />			
			<stat name="additional:hp:max" value="level:ranger" />
			<stat name="additional:hp:max" value="level:ranger" />
			<stat name="additional:hp:max" value="level:ranger" />
			<stat name="additional:hp:max" value="level:ranger" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="additional:hp:max" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Exceptional Training" type="Archetype Feature" source="Offline Knights" id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_EXCEPTIONAL_TRAINING">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_RANGER_BEASTMASTER_EXCEPTIONAL_TRAINING</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 7th level, on any of your turns when your beast companion doesn’t attack, you can use a bonus action to command the beast to take the Dash, Disengage, or Help action on its turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, the beast’s attacks now count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>On any of your turns when your beast companion doesn’t attack, you can command the beast to take the Dash, Disengage, or Help action on its turn.
			The beast’s attacks now count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Bestial Fury" type="Archetype Feature" source="Offline Knights" id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_BESTIAL_FURY">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_RANGER_BEASTMASTER_BESTIAL_FURY</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 11th level, when you command your beast companion to take the Attack action, the beast can make two attacks, or it can take the Multiattack action if it has that action.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you command your beast companion to take the Attack action, the beast can make two attacks, or it can take the Multiattack action if it has that action.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Share Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Offline Knights" id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_SHARE_SPELLS">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_RANGER_BEASTMASTER_SHARE_SPELLS</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 15th level, when you cast a spell targeting yourself, you can also affect your beast companion with the spell if the beast is within 30 feet of you.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you cast a spell targeting yourself, you can also affect your beast companion with the spell if the beast is within 30 feet of you.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!--Feature Replacement Grants-->
	<element name="Primal Companion Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_RANGER_BEAST_MASTER_PRIMAL_COMPANION" />
	<element name="Exceptional Training Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_RANGER_BEASTMASTER_EXCEPTIONAL_TRAINING" />
	<element name="Bestial Fury Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_RANGER_BEASTMASTER_BESTIAL_FURY" />
	<element name="Share Spells Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_RANGER_BEASTMASTER_SHARE_SPELLS" />
</elements>
